<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on POLOXUE's BLOG</title><link>https://en.poloxue.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on POLOXUE's BLOG</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Polo Xue All rights reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 17:47:23 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://en.poloxue.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Exploring High-Efficiency int to string Conversion Strategies and Source Code in Go</title><link>https://en.poloxue.com/posts/2024-01-20-int-to-string-in-golang/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 17:47:23 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://en.poloxue.com/posts/2024-01-20-int-to-string-in-golang/</guid><description>In Go, converting an integer (int) to a string (string) is a common operation.
This post will introduce several common methods to convert int to string in Go, focusing on the performance characteristics of these methods. It will also delve into the efficient algorithm implementation of FormatInt.
Using strconv.Itoa The most direct and commonly used method is the Itoa function from the strconv package. Itoa is an abbreviation for &amp;ldquo;Integer to ASCII&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>IDE for Go Development: Exploring Features and Popular Options</title><link>https://en.poloxue.com/posts/2024-01-07-why-we-should-use-golang-ide/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 13:23:03 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://en.poloxue.com/posts/2024-01-07-why-we-should-use-golang-ide/</guid><description>Why do programmers need to use an IDE?&amp;quot;
This question frequently surfaces on various community forums. When it comes to whether one should use an Integrated Development Environment (IDE), everyone has their own viewpoint.
In the early days, programming didn&amp;rsquo;t necessitate an IDE as it was primarily centered around machine code. However, as the computer industry progressed, IDEs emerged to enhance engineering development efficiency.
It&amp;rsquo;s essential to grasp that an IDE primarily integrates various command tools into a user-friendly software, facilitating efficient programming practices.</description></item><item><title>Moving Basic Usage: Installation and Video Manipulation</title><link>https://en.poloxue.com/posts/2024-01-06-moving-basic-usage/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 00:09:46 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://en.poloxue.com/posts/2024-01-06-moving-basic-usage/</guid><description>In an era dominated by short-form videos, numerous user-friendly editing software options exist.
However, for specialized video formats like eBook presentations or comic readings, streamlining the video creation process through automation stands as a crucial enhancement for efficiency.
In this tutorial, we&amp;rsquo;ll delve into MoviePy, a Python library designed to automate video production processes. We&amp;rsquo;ll explore its capabilities and demonstrate how it simplifies video editing tasks through simple Python code.</description></item><item><title>Setup Your Own iTerm2 - Install iTerm2 and Configure Its Color Presets</title><link>https://en.poloxue.com/posts/2023-10-11-setup-your-own-iterm2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 10:22:36 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://en.poloxue.com/posts/2023-10-11-setup-your-own-iterm2/</guid><description>Hi guys, This is POLO X.
Today, I plan to talk about how to install iTerm2 and configure iTerm2 color presets. At the end of the post, there will be some tips about iTerm2 to share with you.
What is iTerm2? Quote from the official site.
iTerm2 is a replacement for Terminal and the successor to iTerm. It works on Macs with macOS 10.14 or newer. iTerm2 brings the terminal into the modern age with features you never knew you always wanted.</description></item><item><title>Autostart Tmux in iTerm2 - Improve Your Productivity</title><link>https://en.poloxue.com/posts/2023-09-15-autostart-tmux-in-iterm2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 21:22:36 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://en.poloxue.com/posts/2023-09-15-autostart-tmux-in-iterm2/</guid><description>This post will introduce how to autostart Tmux when starting iTerm2.
By default, every time you start iTerm2, you need to enter tmux attach to enter tmux mode.
I use Tmux to manage workspaces for different projects. Common IDEs generally provide an interface for users to select projects. Naturally, can iTerm2 + Tmux have a similar function?
Very simple!
Solution 1: A single-line shell script First, let&amp;rsquo;s see a bash script:</description></item></channel></rss>